A Guide to the Population Council records, Accession 1, RG 1 FA210
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Accession 1, 1
  - Organization File, 1956-1966; 4
    - United States
      - Department of Agriculture - World Food Forum, 1962 (Box 115, Folder 2112)
      - Department of Commerce, 1965 (Box 115, Folder 2113)
      - Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1963-1966 (Box 115, Folder 2114-2115)
      - Department of Health, Education and Welfare - National Cancer Institute, 1964-1966 (Box 115, Folder 2116-2117)
      - Department of Health, Education and Welfare - Public Health Service, 1963-1966 (Box 116, Folder 2118-2120)
      - Department of Health, Education and Welfare - Public Health Service - National Center for Health Statistics, 1963-1966 (Box 116, Folder 2121-2124)
      - Department of Labor, 1964 (Box 116, Folder 2125)
      - Department of State, 1956-1966 (Box 116, Folder 2126-2128)
      - Family Planning, 1964 (Box 116, Folder 2129)
      - Information Agency (USIA), 1966 (Box 116, Folder 2130)
      - Miscellany, 1963-1966 (Box 116, Folder 2121-2132)
      - Office of Economic Opportunity (OEO), 1966 (Box 116, Folder 2133)
      - Patents, 1963-1965 (Box 116, Folder 2134)
      - White House, 1964-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2135)
    - University of Arizona, 1964 (Box 117, Folder 2136)
    - University of Arkansas, 1964 (Box 117, Folder 2137)
    - University of California
      - General Material, 1963-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2138-2140)
      - Clark, Elizabeth, 1963-1965 (Box 117, Folder 2141)
      - Davis, Kingsley, 1963 (Box 117, Folder 2142)
      - Griffiths, William, 1963-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2143-2144)
      - Roberts, Beryl, 1963-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2145)
      - Smith, Charles E., 1963-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2146)
      - Wallace, Helen M., 1963-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2147-2148)
    - University of Chicago
      - General Material, 1963-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2149-2150)
      - Bogue, Donald, 1961-1966 (Box 117, Folder 2151-2153)
      - Computer Application to Demography, 1964 (Box 118, Folder 2154)
      - Computer Utilization - Grant Proposal, 1963-1964 (Box 118, Folder 2155-2156)
    - University of Chicago
      - Hauser, Philip, 1963-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2157-2158)
      - International Congress of Human Genetics (III), 1966 (Box 118, Folder 2159-2160)
      - Keyfitz, Nathan, 1964-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2161)
    - University of Colorado, 1963-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2162)
    - University of Connecticut, 1964-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2163)
    - University of Hawaii, 1966 (Box 118, Folder 2164)
    - University of Hawaii - Center for Cultural and Technical Exchange Between East and West, 1963-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2165-2166)
    - University of Hawaii - Conference on Public Health Training in Asian Countries, 1965 (Box 118, Folder 2167-2168)
    - University of Hawaii - Grant Proposal, 1963-1965 (Box 118, Folder 2169)
    - University of Illinois, 1963-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2170)
    - University of Kansas, 1963-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2171-2172)
    - University of Massachusetts, 1963-1966 (Box 118, Folder 2173-2174)
    - University of Michigan
      - General Material, 1963-1966 (Box 119, Folder 2175-2177)
      - Corsa, Leslie, 1963-1966 (Box 119, Folder 2178-2179)
      - Freedman, Ronald, 1963-1966 (Box 119, Folder 2180-2182)
      - Freedman, Ronald - Travel, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 2183)
      - Population Studies Center, 1966 (Box 119, Folder 2184)
      - Taiwan Day, 1966 (Box 119, Folder 2185)
      - Takeshita, John Y., 1964-1966 (Box 119, Folder 2186-2187)
    - University of Missouri, 1966 (Box 119, Folder 2188)
    - University of North Carolina, 1962-1965 (Box 119, Folder 2189)
    - University of North Carolina, 1965-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2190-2191)
    - University of Notre Dame, 1963-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2192-2193)
    - University of Notre Dame - Grant Proposal, 1963 (Box 120, Folder 2194)
    - University of Oregon, 1963-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2195)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1963-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2196-2197)
    - University of Pennsylvania - Graduate Program in Demography - Grant Proposal, 1966 (Box 120, Folder 2198)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1963-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2199-2200)
    - University of Southern California, 1963-1965 (Box 120, Folder 2201-2202)
    - University of Tennessee, 1963 (Box 120, Folder 2203)
    - University of Tennessee - Groves Conference, 1964 (Box 120, Folder 2204-2205)
    - University of Texas, 1963-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2206-2207)
    - University of Washington, 1964-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2208-2209)
    - University of West Virginia, 1965-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2210)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1963-1966 (Box 120, Folder 2211-2212)
    - Vanderbilt University, 1965 (Box 120, Folder 2213)
    - Vincent Astor Foundation, 1960 (Box 121, Folder 2214)
    - Washington University, 1965-1966 (Box 121, Folder 2215)
    - Webb Institute for Medical Research, 1963-1965 (Box 121, Folder 2216)
    - Williams College - Roper Center, 1964-1965 (Box 121, Folder 2217)
    - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology, 1963-1964 (Box 121, Folder 2218-2219)
    - World Federation for Mental Health, 1963 (Box 121, Folder 2220)
    - World Neighbors, 1963-1966 (Box 121, Folder 2221-2222)
    - Yale University, 1963-1966 (Box 121, Folder 2223)
  - Subject File, 1955-1966; 5
    Consists of a small set of files on miscellaneous topics. They relate to both the administration of Council affairs and to the involvement in matters directly related to family planning. Among the important files are those covering contraceptive development and testing and donations to the Council.
    Arranged in alphabetical order by folder title.
    Former Classification: IV 3B 04.6
    See also: FA432 Population Council records, Accession 2, Series 4: Subject File, for records dating from 1967-1976.
    Indexing to the Subject File is provided by FA775 Population Council records, Index, Series 2: Central File Index, 1961-1976.
    - Abortion Study Committee, 1966 (Box 122, Folder 2224)
    - Canfield, Cass, 1961-1963 (Box 122, Folder 2225)
    - Conference Topics and Announcements - Conferences Sponsored by Various Organizations, Including Population Council, 1962-1963 (Box 122, Folder 2226)
    - Conference Topics and Announcements - Invitations to Population Council (Arranged Alphabetically by Sponsoring Organization), 1959-1966 (Box 122, Folder 2227-2228)
    - Conferences
      - Conference of Committee on Economic Growth - Social Science Research Council, 1962 (Box 122, Folder 2229-2230)
      - Conference on Immuno-Reproduction, 1962-1963 (Box 122, Folder 2231-2232)
      - Conference on Intrauterine Contraception, 1964-1965 (Box 122, Folder 2233-2235)
        Second International Conference on Intrauterine Contraception, New York, October 2-3, 1964.
        Scope and Contents
        Includes correspondence with Dr. Katherine Kuder.
      - Conference on Strategy for Implementing Family Planning in Developing Countries, 1964 (Box 122, Folder 2236)
      - Conference on Teaching of Genetics to Medical Students, 1961 (Box 122, Folder 2237)
      - International Conference on Family Planning - Pre-Belgrade Conference, 1964 (Box 122, Folder 2238)
      - International Conference on Family Planning, Geneva - Publication of Proceedings, 1966 (Box 122, Folder 2239)
    - Consultants
      - Baumgartner, Leona, 1958-1962 (Box 122, Folder 2240-2241)
      - Bronnenkant, Paul, 1964-1966 (Box 122, Folder 2242)
      - Clemens, George S., 1966-1967 (Box 122, Folder 2243-2244)
      - Denniston, George, 1966 (Box 123, Folder 2245)
      - Taeuber, Irene, 1959-1966 (Box 123, Folder 2246-2247)
      - Tatum, Howard J., 1965-1967 (Box 123, Folder 2248-2249)
      - Zilkha and Sons, 1962 (Box 123, Folder 2250)
    - Contraception
      - General Material, 1960-1966 (Box 123, Folder 2251)
      - Baby Planning Beads, 1963-1964 (Box 123, Folder 2252)
      - Coils, 1963-1966 (Box 123, Folder 2253-2257)
      - Intrauterine Device Survey, 1966 (Box 123, Folder 2258-2259)
      - Oral Contraceptives, 1959-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2260-2261)
      - Oral Contraceptives G. D. Searle and Company, 1964-1967 (Box 124, Folder 2262-2264)
    - Contraception - Coils - Patents
      - General Material, 1965-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2265)
      - Hong Kong, 1965-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2266)
    - Contraception - Coils - Patents
      - India, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 2267)
      - Pakistan, 1965-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2268)
      - South Korea, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 2269)
      - Sri Lanka (Ceylon), 1966 (Box 124, Folder 2270)
      - Turkey, 1965-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2271)
    - Contraception - Intrauterine Device Manufacture
      - General Material, 1964-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2272)
      - Hallmark Plastics, Incorporated Bronnenkant, 1964-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2273)
      - Hallmark Plastics, Incorporated - Status Reports, 1966 (Box 124, Folder 2274)
    - Contraceptives - Manufacturers
      - British Drug Houses, Limited (The), 1966 (Box 124, Folder 2275)
      - Distribution Survey, 1962 (Box 124, Folder 2276-2277)
      - Durex Products, Incorporated, 1962-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2278)
      - Eli Lilly and Company, 1966 (Box 124, Folder 2279)
      - Farmitalia, 1965-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2280)
      - G. D. Searle and Company, 1965-1967 (Box 124, Folder 2281-2282)
      - India - Hanspal, I. Singh, 1960 (Box 124, Folder 2283-2284)
      - Laboratorios Hormona, South America, 1966 (Box 124, Folder 2285)
      - London Rubber Industries, Limited, 1966-1967 (Box 124, Folder 2286-2287)
      - Mead Johnson and Company, 1965-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2288)
      - Merck and Company, 1965-1966 (Box 124, Folder 2289)
      - Miscellaneous Companies, Associations, Offices, 1965-1968 (Box 124, Folder 2290-2291)
      - Miscellaneous Companies; Council - Survey of Products, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 2292)
      - Organon Laboratories, Limited, 1965-1967 (Box 125, Folder 2293-2294)
      - Ortho Pharmaceutical Corporation, 1963-1967 (Box 125, Folder 2295-2296)
      - Parke, Davis Company, 1965-1966 (Box 125, Folder 2297)
      - Roussel/UCLAF, South America, 1966-1967 (Box 125, Folder 2298-2299)
      - Schering Ag Berlin, 1966-1967 (Box 125, Folder 2300-2301)
      - Syntex, 1965-1967 (Box 125, Folder 2302-2303)
      - Upjohn, Incorporated, 1965-1966 (Box 125, Folder 2304)
      - Wyeth International, Limited, 1966 (Box 125, Folder 2305)
    - Donations - Requests to Population Council, 1960-1965 (Box 125, Folder 2306-2307)
    - Donors
      - General Material, 1960-1966 (Box 125, Folder 2308-2309)
      - Faulkner, Mrs. James M., 1962-1964 (Box 125, Folder 2310-2311)
      - Lee, Mrs. Weston C., 1958-1960 (Box 125, Folder 2312)
      - Mauz, Mrs. Abby Rockefeller, 1960-1966 (Box 125, Folder 2313-2314)
      - May, Cordelia Scaife and Scaife, Cordelia, 1960-1966 (Box 125, Folder 2315-2318)
      - May, Cordelia Scaife and Scaife, Cordelia - Travel to Asia, 1962-1964 (Box 126, Folder 2319)
      - May, Cordelia Scaife and Scaife, Cordelia - University Endowments, 1965-1966 (Box 126, Folder 2320-2321)
      - Prospects, 1962-1965 (Box 126, Folder 2322)
      - Rockefeller, David, 1966 (Box 126, Folder 2323)
      - Rockefeller, David Jr., 1963-1966 (Box 126, Folder 2324)
      - Spencer, Mr. and Mrs. John, 1964-1966 (Box 126, Folder 2325)
      - White, Roger T., 1961-1962 (Box 126, Folder 2326)
    - Elizabeth Telsey Company (The) - Cata Recorder, 1957-1960 (Box 126, Folder 2327)
    - Ernst, Morris, 1960-1962 (Box 126, Folder 2328)
    - Evaluation Manual, 1964-1965 (Box 126, Folder 2329)
    - Family Planning - Manual and Film Strips, 1963-1965 (Box 126, Folder 2330)
    - Fellowships - Medical Genetics
      - American Eugenics Society Fellowship Committee, 1958-1961 (Box 126, Folder 2331-2332)
      - Applications, 1958-1961 (Box 126, Folder 2333)
      - Hirschhorn, Kurt, 1956-1958 (Box 126, Folder 2334)
    - Films - National Educational Television and Radio Center, Population Series, 1962-1964 (Box 126, Folder 2335-2336)
    - Films - National Educational Television and Radio Center, Population Series, 1963-1965 (Box 127, Folder 2337-2338)
    - Grants
      - General Material, 1958-1966 (Box 127, Folder 2339)
      - Balances, 1958 1961-1966 (Box 127, Folder 2340-2341)
      - Listing of Grants to Latin American Institutions, 1958-1966 (Box 127, Folder 2342)
      - Postpartum Clinics, 1965-1966 (Box 127, Folder 2343)
    - Growth of American Family (GAF) Survey, 1961 (Box 127, Folder 2344)
    - History, 1952-1964 (Box 127, Folder 2345)
    - Information Program, 1962 1965 (Box 127, Folder 2346-2347)
    - Legal Matters, 1966 (Box 127, Folder 2348)
    - Mobile Unit - Tunisia, 1966 (Box 127, Folder 2349)
    - Personnel - Selegen, Galina V., 1959-1960 (Box 127, Folder 2350*)
    - Population Meeting - Minutes, 1966 January 7 (Box 127, Folder 2351)
    - Postpartum Program - Target Population, 1966 (Box 127, Folder 2352)
    - Questionnaires - Asia-Sweden - Ceylon Family Planning Project, 1960 (Box 127, Folder 2353)
    - Questionnaires - Distribution, 1966 (Box 127, Folder 2354)
    - Religious Attitudes Toward Birth Control - Catholic Views - Gibbons, William, 1958-1961 (Box 127, Folder 2355-2356)
    - Research
      - Council Cooperation With Public Health Schools, 1959 (Box 127, Folder 2357-2358)
      - Medicine, 1960-1962 (Box 127, Folder 2359)
      - Psychological Determinants of Fertility - Proposed Conference, 1961 (Box 127, Folder 2360)
    - Staff Meetings
      - Minutes and Agendas, 1956-1963 (Box 128, Folder 2361-2362)
      - Morocco and Tunisia Programs August, 1966 (Box 128, Folder 2363)
      - The Population Council Retreat Meeting Concerning Policy, 1965 (Box 128, Folder 2364)
    - Television - CBS, 1963 (Box 128, Folder 2365)
    - Twelve Year Report of Population Council - Preparation, 1964-1965 (Box 128, Folder 2366)
    - Twelve Year Report of Population Council - Recipients, 1965 (Box 128, Folder 2367)
    - Victor, Alexander - Estate, 1961-1962 (Box 128, Folder 2368-2369)
    - Closed Files (Box 129)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Boxes 129-130 contain personnel records and/or records which reveal the names of patients or participants in medical studies.
      According to the criteria set for the Population Council collection review conducted in January 2001, these records remain restricted from scholarly access.
    - Closed Files (Box 130)